Guide to the Stan Healy Photographs and Papers 1890s-1990s (bulk 1940s-1970s)
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
- Accession 2021-048, circa 1930s-1990s; Series II; 4.0 linear feet (1,313 images)
  - Papers, 1935-1984; Subseries 3
    - Link Trainer notes, 1941-1942; Binder with Stan's flight simulation notes; recorded during his time at the University of Montana in Missoula and his U.S. Army Air Corps training at Sheppard Field, Texas, Fort Douglas, Utah, Chanute Field, Illinois, and Paine Field, Washington. (Box-folder 13 / 5)
    - Link Trainer grades and exercise log, May-June 1942; Stan's grades and remarks from his Air Corps training exercises at Chanute Field, Illinois (Box-folder 13 / 6)
    - Letters to Stan Healy, 1942-1943; Letters from friends to Stan Healy during his time in the Army Air Force (Box-folder 13 / 7)
    - Certificates, circa 1945-1978; Certificates of appreciation and completion from the Army Air Forces, Missoula County High School, University of Montana, Governor's office, and the American Hospital Association for various achievements (Box-folder 13 / 8)
    - Missoula Sentinel newspaper clippings, June 1955 (Box-folder 13 / 9)
    - Letter, Missoula Mayor to property owners, July 1, 1955; Letter from Missoula Mayor James Hart discussing "wild" rumors about the city's plan to improve West Front Street; handwritten memo reads: "Late Saturday Scoop" (Box-folder 13 / 10)
    - Missoula City Council notes and agendas, May-November 1959; Two steno pads with Stan's notes from Missoula City Council meetings; some agendas are pasted into one of the notebooks; other agendas are loose (Box-folder 13 / 11-13)
    - Juvenile arrest statistics, October 2, 1959; Juvenile arrests in Missoula broken down by offense for the month of September 1959 (Box-folder 13 / 14)
    - Missoula City Council tips for preventing fires, circa 1959 (Box-folder 13 / 15)
    - Writings re: cross dressing, circa 1960s; Short piece written by Stan about his pleasures, copy of Transvestia, and other clippings (Box-folder 13 / 16)
    - Letters re: Higgins Avenue Bridge Project, February-March, 1960; Letters from the Montana State Highway Commission and the State Board of Health to the City of Missoula about the Higgins Avenue Bridge project (Box-folder 13 / 17)
    - North Side Progressive League scrapbook, 1966; Stan's scrapbook about the mission and accomplishments of the Missoula Northside Progressive League; Stan served as the vice president and publicity chair of the group in the 1960s (Box-folder 13 / 18)
    - Letter, Northern Pacific Railway Company to Stan Healy, March 26, 1968; Letter about service discontinuance and Stan's photos being used as evidence in proceedings with the Interstate Commerce Commission (Box-folder 13 / 19)
    - Public comments, Stan Healy to the Missoula City Council, June 25, 1984; Stan's comments made at Missoula City Council meeting protesting plans to move streets on the North Side (Box-folder 13 / 20)
    - Campaign material, undated; "Healy is not satisfied with Missoula's Streets. Elect Stan Healy-Democrat, Ward 2 Alderman (North and West Side)" and "Stan Healy (Hell-raiser) for Resident Council President." (Box-folder 13 / 21)
- Charles F. Buls Family Photographs, circa 1890s; Series III; 0.75 linear feet (37 images)
  Series III features 37 glass plate negatives of the Stan Healy’s maternal grandparents, Charles and Cecilia Buls, and their children, including Healy’s mother Emma. Charles and Cecilia immigrated to Missoula, Montana from Germany in the 1890s, where Charles worked as a railroader for the Northern Pacific Railway and as a prospector. He later gained principle control of the Tarbox Mine on Packer Creek. In addition to the family photos, a few glass plate negatives in this series document Glacier and Yellowstone National Parks.
  - Emma Buls and (sister?) at the piano, circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 192)
  - Buls family posed in their sitting room, circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 193)
  - Charles and Cecilia Buls posed with their daughters?, circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 194)
  - Charles and Cecilia Buls posed with their daughters?, circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 195)
  - Cecilia Buls and daugther posed in front of their house, circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 196)
  - Buls family in front of their house, circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 197)
  - Buls family in front of their house, circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 198)
  - Buls family in front of their house, circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 199)
  - Men standing on (Buls family?) porch, circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 200)
  - Charles Buls and (daughter?) standing on (Buls family?) porch, circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 201)
  - Railroad construction in front of Buls family house, circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 202)
  - Northern Pacific train, circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 203)
  - Train tracks, circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 204)
  - Buls family outing on the creek, circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 205)
  - Buls family in the woods, circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 206)
  - Buls family in the woods, circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 207)
  - Men driving a horse-drawn carriage, circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 208)
  - Group of people in the woods, circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 209)
  - Men working outside, circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 210)
  - Men doing survey work?, circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 211)
  - Men posed next to a deer carcas, circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 212)
  - Deer carcus, circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 213)
  - Three men painting an interior space, circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 214)
  - Men posed in front of a store counter with a Missoula baseball sign in the background, circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 215)
  - Group posed on a porch, circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 216)
  - Girls in the woods playing marching band instruments, circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 217)
  - Portrait of (Buls matriarch?), circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 218)
  - Portrait of (Buls matriarch?), circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 219)
  - Portrait of a baby, circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 220)
  - Aerial view of Missoula, Montana, circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 221)
  - Ornate church interior?, circa 1890s (Box 14, Photo number 430 (III): 222)
  - Tower Falls, Yellowstone National Park, undated (Box 8, Photo number 430 (III): 223)
  - Grotto Geyser, Yellowstone National Park, undated (Box 8, Photo number 430 (III): 224)
  - Glacier National Park, undated (Box 8, Photo number 430 (III): 225)
  - Glacier National Park, undated (Box 8, Photo number 430 (III): 226)
  - Bowl of apples, undated (Box 8, Photo number 430 (III): 227)
  - Kitchen counter, undated (Box 8, Photo number 430 (III): 228)